I was wondering about unwholesome and
Coulson's because you say that our folks
are caused by acting mostly so to
overcome once folks and then wholesome
behavior which become self transparent [Music]
it's so easy to do the transparency
transparency there to be to be
constantly watchful of your intentions
while you go about your day
quite difficult business the correct way
well the first the first point I would
address would be you mentioned in the
things of faults or thing can be
regarded as a fault if it's rooted in
greed aversion or delusion so that
basically a definition of a fault so
even if something is universally
accepted socially accepted to be done
and normal if it's rooted and agreed
aversion delusion from the point of view
develop in your mind that is unwholesome
so that's where this self transparency
in regard to the motives behind you
wanting to do things that's what that
self transparency is necessary yeah it's
a it's necessary as a basis and then
actually it is it is necessary for
rather you don't have to look for
anything other than that basis to
develop your mind in other words the
criteria that you will be using to
develop the self transparency is the
criteria you can use all the way to the
complete development of your mind that
transparency so it is definitely
something to be done starting from the
from your bodily actions that you start
developing what phone and cell
mindfulness in regard to things we want
to do in your body and see where where
is that action rooted or where would it
be rooted why do I want to do this so
initially you might have to kind of do
it excessively in terms of interrogating
yourself but once that attitude becomes
established you don't have to think
about the questions why am I doing this
so because of the you just looking at it
would be already a form of a form of
investigating the motivation which means
just by looking at it you would be
seeing where it is rooted
so if you want to do something by the
with media building in terms of on what
I want to go somewhere or I want to eat
something what I want to be working or
whatever you have to ask yourself why
why do I want to do this then you might
say well because other people need my
help is like okay so then the further so why
is like okay so then the further so why
why are you the one in the position of
giving your help to others and so on
doesn't mean like you you have to
classify it as all this is good or this
is bad all you want to do is just be
fully transparent when it comes down to
knowing why you're doing whatever you're
doing because that's how you will start
to sieve out many many unwholesome
things that people end up doing
habitually because they never look at
the reasons why they're doing them so
they just go with it and then the that
and the proliferating and getting worse
and worse and then people acquire all
sorts of habits and unwholesome things
sensuality and it will just because they
never really looked at it never saw
themselves doing it you can put it that
way
so going okay yeah that's that's a kind
of it's a neutral example there's
nothing in nothing model about watching
a movie there is nothing even ethically
wrong to go and watch a movie but
include somebody who wants to develop
their mind in terms of complete freedom
from suffering or things with into the
down practice then yeah like you can say
Oh everybody watches the movie it's fine
and then pretend that that's it that's
all to it and then go and watch a movie
or you can ask well everybody is not me
and everybody is not practicing for me
so why am I going to do it why why do I
want to do it and if you if you discover
that the motive behind you is just
distraction because feels a bit too
heavy being alone or something and then
you want to go out and watch movie night
as well as I said it's nothing immoral
but from the ultimate point of view of
freedom of the mind freedom
of the month from the census that is
that is an obstacle because you are
giving in to the distraction you want to
distract us that you want to you want to
engage in an attitude of delusion of
non-transparency because it's it's it's
a bit too boring to just be all the time
line for something like that and then
you give in to it but if you're focused
and so like you know some somebody might
hear this in the Orcas I'll never watch
a movie again
no that's not the point the point is you
should never forget about the reasons
why you do things then that principle
that attitude will straighten things out
in itself because if you're never
transparent so if you're always
transparent means you can't delude
yourself anymore which means sooner or
later you start feeling guilty for
constantly distracting yourself and if
you don't compromise the attitude of
transparency then that gift will be
enough to keep you away from things
effortlessly so yes initially you might
need to restrain yourself and say no to
things but that in itself only to any
understanding of the nature things you
developing self transparency regarded
that night